Guide to the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Administration, 1866-1980
  - Department of Transportation
    - Shippers' Conference of Greater New York
      - Petitions
        - 1967-1968 (Box 322, Folder 4)
        - 1969-1974 (Box 322, Folder 5)
  - Events
    - 200th Anniversary
      - General, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 1)
      - Commemorative Medal, 1966-1968 (Box 237, Folder 2)
      - Commemorative Stamp, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 237, Folder 4)
      - Dramatization, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 5)
      - Event Program, 1968 (Box 237, Folder 6)
      - Film, 1966 (Box 237, Folder 7)
      - Invitation to President Lydon B. Johnson, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 8)
      - Logo, 1968 (Box 237, Folder 9)
      - Nation's Business, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 10)
      - The New York Times Supplement, 1967 (Box 237, Folder 11)
      - Planning, 1965-1968 (Box 237, Folder 12)
      - Press Kit, 1968 (Box 237, Folder 13)
      - Public Opening of the Great Hall, 1967-1968 (Box 237, Folder 14)
      - Public Relations, 1968 (Box 237, Folder 15)
      - Requests and Inquiries, 1968-1969 (Box 238, Folder 1)
      - Royal Charter Presentation, 1967 (Box 238, Folder 2)
      - Speeches, 1966-1968 (Box 238, Folder 3)
      - "The First Two Centuries... " Historical Brochure, 1968 (Box 238, Folder 4)
    - Annual Banquet--Subscribers/Guest Books
      - 1924 (bound volume) (Box 380)
      - 1925 (bound volume) (Box 381)
      - Applications to Bring Guests, 1925 (bound volume) (Box 382)
      - 1926 (bound volume) (Box 384)
      - 1927 (bound volume) (Box 383)
      - 1928 (bound volume) (Box 385)
      - 1929 (bound volume) (Box 386)
      - 1930 (bound volume) (Box 387)
      - 1931 (bound volume) (Box 388)
      - 1932 (bound volume) (Box 389)
      - 1933 (bound volume) (Box 428)
    - Conferences
      - Civil Rights, Forum on, 1964 (Box 324, Folder 1)
      - Crime Situation, 1922 (Box 324, Folder 2)
      - Crime Situation, 1922 (Box 238, Folder 5)
      - Discrimination Against North Atlantic and the Railroads, 1920 (Box 238, Folder 6)
      - Diversion of Export Freight From New York to Other Ports, 1920 (Box 238, Folder 7)
      - Fifth International Congress of Chambers of Commerce, 1912 (Box 328, Folder 7)
      - The Economic Outlook Forum, 1971 (Box 328, Folder 8)
      - Increased Subway Fare, 1947 (Box 324, Folder 3)
      - International Joint Commission of the Proposed St. Lawrence Canal, 1920 (Box 324, Folder 4)
      - New York State Commercial Organizations, 1921-1922 (Box 238, Folder 8)
      - New York State Delegation--National Rivers and Harbors Congress, 1922 (Box 238, Folder 9)
      - Opportunities in Economic Development, undated (Box 324, Folder 5)
      - Pensions for Employees, 1950 (Box 328, Folder 9)
      - Public Health Committee of New York Academy of Medicine, 1921 (Box 238, Folder 10)
      - Relief of Traffic Congestion, 1924 (Box 238, Folder 11)
      - Representatives of Commercial Organizations, 1922 (Box 324, Folder 6)
      - Tax Crisis Facing New York City and New York State, A Symposium on the, 1964 (Box 324, Folder 7)
      - World Trade Forum--Canada-United States Trade Relations, 1949 (Box 324, Folder 8)
    - Dinners
      - Morgan, Postmaster Edward M., 1923 (Box 239, Folder 1)
      - Representatives in Congress from New York State, 1918 (Box 239, Folder 2)
    - Essay Contests
      - General
        - 1920-1923 (Box 324, Folder 9)
        - 1954-1958 (Box 324, Folder 10)
        - 1963 (Box 324, Folder 11)
        - 1964 (Box 324, Folder 12)
        - 1966 (Box 324, Folder 13)
        - 1967 (Box 324, Folder 14)
        - 1968 (Box 324, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence
        - 1962-1963 (Box 324, Folder 16)
        - 1963-1964 (Box 324, Folder 17)
      - Graduate Contest--Fruend, William C., 1952 (Box 324, Folder 18)
      - Winners, 1943 (Box 324, Folder 19)
    - Invitations and Programs
      - 1867-1889 (Box 215, Folder 1)
      - 1890-1894 (Box 215, Folder 2)
      - 1895-1899 (Box 215, Folder 3)
      - 1900-1905 (Box 215, Folder 4)
      - 1906-1910 (Box 215, Folder 5)
      - 1911-1915 (Box 216, Folder 1)
      - 1916-1922 (Box 216, Folder 2)
      - 1923-1925 (Box 216, Folder 3)
      - 1926-1929 (Box 216, Folder 4)
      - 1930-1934 (Box 217, Folder 1)
      - 1935-1940 (Box 217, Folder 2)
      - 1941-1976 (Box 217, Folder 3)
    - Luncheons
      - Bush, Irving T.--The European Situation, 1923 (Box 239, Folder 3)
      - Calles, Elias, 1924 (Box 328, Folder 10)
      - Chamber Activities, 1923 (Box 239, Folder 4)
      - Consider the Raising of Business Standards, 1922 (Box 239, Folder 5)
      - Culbertson, William S., 1945 (Box 328, Folder 11)
      - Delegates to the Second Pan-American Financial Conference, 1920 (Box 239, Folder 6)
      - Dempsey, Wallace--Rivers and Harbors Committee, 1922-1923 (Box 239, Folder 7)
      - Edward, Prince of Wales, 1919-1920 (Box 239, Folder 8)
      - Fujiyama, Raita, President of the Tokio [sic] Chamber of Commerce, 1923 (Box 239, Folder 9)
      - George, David Lloyd, 1923 (Box 239, Folder 10)
      - Luncheon and Special Meeting--Ports of New York and New Jersey, 1920 (Box 239, Folder 11)
      - Members' Council, 1979 (Box 328, Folder 12)
      - Membership Growth, 1921-1922 (Box 239, Folder 12)
      - New York Yankees, 1967-1971 (Box 239, Folder 13)
      - President and Vice President of the San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 1920 (Box 239, Folder 14)
      - Von Miller, Oskar--Deutshe Museum, 1925 (Box 239, Folder 15)
      - Safeguarding Small Investors, 1922-1923 (Box 239, Folder 16)
    - Receptions
      - Cosmopolitan Club, 1923 (Box 239, Folder 17)
      - Harding, President Warren G., 1923 (Box 239, Folder 18)
      - Henry, Prince of Prussia, 1902 (Box 239, Folder 19)
      - Henry, Prince of Prussia--Committee, 1901-1906 (Box 239, Folder 20)
  - Financial Matters
    - Analysis of Investments, 1969-1970 (Box 328, Folder 13)
    - Bills Approved for Services Rendered, 1886 March-1905 April (bound volume) (Box 445)
    - Bills Audited for Services Rendered, 1874 February-1886 March (bound volume) (Box 446)
    - Building Fund Bonds, 1947-1948 (Box 318, Folder 7)
    - Directors’ Trust Committee, 1966 (Box 328, Folder 14)
    - Equity Conservation Corporation--Fund Mortgage, 1939 (Box 318, Folder 8)
    - Fidelity Bond, 1941 (Box 318, Folder 9)
    - Financial Reports
      - 1910 (Box 218, Folder 1)
      - 1927-1929 (Box 218, Folder 2)
      - 1940-1950 (Box 218, Folder 3)
      - 1951-1960 (Box 218, Folder 4)
      - 1961-1963 1967-1968 (Box 218, Folder 5)
    - Funds
      - 1919-1937 (Box 218, Folder 6)
      - 1952 (Box 218, Folder 7)
      - Hepburn Fund, 1945-1952 (Box 218, Folder 8)
      - Hepburn Fund, 1945-1955 (Box 318, Folder 10)
      - Income and Fund Balance, 1962-1974 (Box 318, Folder 11)
      - Special Funds, 1945-1977 (Box 318, Folder 12)
    - Legal Issues, 1930-1940 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    - Memorandums--B.C. Davis, 1952-1956 (Box 318, Folder 13)
    - Mortgages, 1939, (2 Folders) (Box 219, Folder 2-3)
    - New Systems of Accounts, 1926-1927 (Box 219, Folder 4)
    - "Pay the Mortgage" Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 219, Folder 5)
    - Subscriber Books-- Subscriptions toward Christmas Fund for Luncheon Room Employees
      - 1923-1925 (bound volume) (Box 390)
      - 1926-1927 (bound volume) (Box 391)
    - Tax Reduction/Exemption, 1945-1947 (Box 219, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer
      - General Statements
        - 1874-1884 (Box 334, Folder 12)
        - 1910-1915, (2 Folders) (Box 334, Folder 13-14)
      - Receipts and Disbursements, 1902-1914 (Box 334, Folder 15)
    - Treasury Department, 1937 (Box 219, Folder 7)
  - Merger with Commerce and Industry Association of New York, Inc.
    - General
      - 1964, (3 Folders) (Box 312, Folder 1-3)
      - 1964-1974 (Box 312, Folder 4)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 312, Folder 5)
    - "An Examination of the Feasibility of the Proposed Merger," 1964 (Box 312, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting, 1964 (Box 312, Folder 7)
    - Ballots
      - Consolidation, 1964 (Box 313, Folder 1)
      - Meeting Adjournment, 1964 (Box 313, Folder 2)
    - Classification of Membership, 1947 (Box 313, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1945-1947 (Box 313, Folder 4)
      - 1964, (2 Folders) (Box 313, Folder 5-6)
      - Member Opposition, 1964 (Box 313, Folder 7)
      - Riegelman, Harold, 1947 (Box 313, Folder 8)
      - Memorandum, 1947 (Box 313, Folder 9)
    - Finances, 1973 (Box 313, Folder 10)
    - "Proposed Consolidation of the Corporation of the Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York and Commerce and Industry Association of New York, Inc.,"1964, (3 Folders) (Box 314, Folder 1-3)
    - Proposed Merger with the New York Board of Trade, 1953-1958 (Box 314, Folder 4)
    - Study, 1936-1948 (Box 314, Folder 5)
    - Study--Historical, 1947 (Box 314, Folder 6)
    - Voting, 1964, (2 Folders) (Box 314, Folder 7-8)
  - Monthly Meetings--Speakers and Speeches
    - Ambrose, Myles J., 1970 November 5 (Box 277, Folder 1)
    - Ball, George W., 1967 May 5 (Box 277, Folder 2)
    - Baring, Lord George Rowland Stanley, 1971 December 2 (Box 277, Folder 3)
    - Bartlett, Dewey, Elliot, Don, and Stans, Maurice H., 1970 January 29 (Box 277, Folder 4)
    - Bentley, Helen Delich, 1971 November 4 (Box 277, Folder 5)
    - Booth, Arch N., 1969 December 4 (Box 277, Folder 6)
    - Buckley, James L., 1971 May 10 (Box 277, Folder 7)
    - Bush, George H., 1973 January 4 (Box 277, Folder 8)
    - Chapin, Roy D., 1972 October 5 (Box 277, Folder 9)
    - Cherne, Leo, 1971 February 4 (Box 277, Folder 10)
    - Connally, John, 1967 March 2 (Box 277, Folder 11)
    - Dean, Sir Patrick, 1968 November 7 (Box 277, Folder 12)
    - Doar, John, 1969 March 6 (Box 277, Folder 13)
    - Fitzhugh, Gilbert W., 1967 December 7 (Box 277, Folder 14)
    - Flanigan, Peter, 1973 February 1 (Box 277, Folder 15)
    - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1967 November 9 (Box 277, Folder 16)
    - Goldwater, Barry, 1972 May 4 (Box 277, Folder 17)
    - Haack, Robert W., 1969 April 3 (Box 277, Folder 18)
    - Hall, Floyd D., 1968 February 1 (Box 277, Folder 19)
    - Hamilton, Edward, 1971 April 1 (Box 277, Folder 20)
    - Hayes, Alfred, 1968 May 2 (Box 277, Folder 21)
    - Hester, James, 1969 May 1 (Box 277, Folder 22)
    - Iacocca, Lee, 1973 February 15 (Box 277, Folder 23)
    - Jordan, Vernon E., 1972 June 1 (Box 277, Folder 24)
    - Kolton, Paul, 1973 March 1 (Box 277, Folder 25)
    - Lindsay, John V., 1967 June 1 (Box 277, Folder 26)
    - Logue, Edward J., 1970 December 9 (Box 277, Folder 27)
    - Luce, Charles F., 1968 December 5 (Box 277, Folder 28)
    - McCracken, Paul W., 1969 October 2 (Box 277, Folder 29)
    - McGill, William J., 1972 April 6 (Box 278, Folder 1)
    - Mills, Wilbur D., 1971 October 8 (Box 278, Folder 2)
    - Murphy, Patrick V., 1970 December 3 (Box 278, Folder 3)
    - Needham, James J., 1972 March 2 (Box 278, Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Sir Leslie, 1968 February 20 (Box 278, Folder 5)
    - Patrick, Thomas W., Jr., 1966 November 3 (Box 278, Folder 6)
    - Peterson, Rudolph A., 1967 April 6 (Box 278, Folder 7)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1966 May 25 (Box 278, Folder 8)
    - Ronan, William J., 1968 October 3 (Box 278, Folder 9)
    - Saul, Ralph S., 1970 April 2 (Box 278, Folder 10)
    - Scranton, William, 1966 February 3 (Box 278, Folder 11)
    - Seymour, Whitney North, 1970 January 7 (Box 278, Folder 12)
    - Stans, Maurice H., 1971 March 4 (Box 278, Folder 13)
    - Tobin, Austin, 1969 February 5 (Box 278, Folder 14)
    - Watson, Thomas, 1967 October 5 (Box 278, Folder 15)
    - Young, Whitney, Jr., 1968 March 7 (Box 278, Folder 16)
  - Public Relations
    - Press Releases
      - 1961-1969 (Box 319, Folder 1)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 319, Folder 2)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 319, Folder 3)
      - 1966-1970 (Box 319, Folder 4)
    - Program Development, 1963-1966 (Box 319, Folder 5)
    - Promotional Materials, 1920-1963 (Box 319, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbooks
      - 1895-1896 (bound volume) (Box 442)
      - 1902 April-1902 November (bound volume) (Box 433)
      - 1902 November-1903 January (bound volume) (Box 444)
      - 1956 October-1957 June (Box 378)
      - 1957 September-1958 September (3 scrapbooks) (Box 378)
      - 1958 January-April (Box 378)
      - 1958 October-1959 December--Books I-III (3 scrapbooks) (Box 379)
      - 1958 February--Hoover Dinner (Box 379)
      - 1960 January-December (Box 393)
  - Realia (Box 376)
    - Medals (Box 376)
      - Abram Stevens Hewitt, 1900
      - The Berwind White Coal Mining Company--50th Anniversary, 1936 (Box 376)
      - Chamber of Commerce--Brussels, 1969 (Box 376)
      - Chamber of Commerce--Paris, undated (Box 376)
      - Charles A. Coffin Medal, 1923 (Box 376)
      - Citizens Budget Commission, 1967 (Box 376)
      - Defenders of Fort Pickens, 1861 (2 medals) (Box 376)
      - Francesco, 1866 (Box 376)
      - The Gary Memorial Medal, undated (Box 376)
      - New York Chamber of Commerce Building Dedication, 1902 (2 medals) (Box 376)
      - New York Stock Exchange, undated (Box 376)
      - Rapid Transit Commission, 1904 (Box 376)
      - The Vail Medal for Noteworthy Public Service, 1920 (Box 376)
    - Pencil, undated (Box 376)
- Series II: Annual Reports, 1858-1975
  The annual reports of the Chamber of Commerce serve as a definitive record of business in the New York region, providing both national and local commercial statistics, yearly accounts of the industry, and special reports on New York trade, commerce, and finance. They also document the activities of the Chamber itself by highlighting noteworthy accomplishments and events of the past year through a compilation of speeches, reports, and narrative summaries. Series II offers a complete run of the Chamber's annual reports from 1858 to 1926; subsequently, only the years 1966-1975 are present.
  - Vol. 1, 1858 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1859-1860 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 3, 1860-1861 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 4, 1861-1862 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 5, 1862-1863 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 6, 1863-1864 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 7, 1864-1865 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 8, 1865-1866 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 9, 1866-1867 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 10, 1867-1868 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 11, 1868-1869 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 12, 1869-1870 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 13, 1870-1871 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 14, 1871-1872 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 15, 1872-1873 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 16, 1873-1874 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 17, 1874-1875 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 18, 1875-1876 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 19, 1876-1877 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 20, 1877-1878 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 21, 1878-1879 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 22, 1879-1880 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 23, 1880-1881 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 24, 1881-1882 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 25, 1882-1883 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 26, 1883-1884 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 27, 1884-1885 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 28, 1885-1886 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 29, 1886-1887 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 30, 1887-1888 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 31, 1888-1889 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 32, 1889-1890 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 33, 1890-1891 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 34, 1891-1892 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 35, 1892-1893 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 36, 1893-1894 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 37, 1894-1895 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 38, 1895-1896 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 39, 1896-1897 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 40, 1897-1898 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 41, 1898-1899 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 42, 1899-1900 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 43, 1900-1901 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 44, 1901-1902 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 45, 1902-1903 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 46, 1903-1904 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 47, 1904-1905 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 48, 1905-1906 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 49, 1906-1907 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 50, 1907-1908 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 51, 1908-1909 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 52, 1909-1910 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 53, 1910-1911 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 54, 1911-1912 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 55, 1912-1913 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 56, 1913-1914 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 57, 1914-1915 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 58, 1915-1916 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 59, 1916-1917 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 60, 1917-1918 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 61, 1918-1919 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 62, 1919-1920 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 63, 1920-1921 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 64, 1921-1922 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 65, 1922-1923 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 66, 1923-1924 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 67, 1924-1925 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 68, 1925-1926 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - 1966-1975 (Box 337, Folder 1)
- Series III: Bulletins, 1909-1970
  The monthly bulletins of the Chamber of Commerce, which make up the third series of the collection, capture a distinctive picture of the Chamber's purpose and actions. This series contains a comprehensive set of bulletins from 1909 to 1963, as well as a few supplemental materials from the 1950s to 1970s. Each bulletin contains information on news and activities of the Chamber, meeting minutes, reports, and library additions. Their initial audience was the organization's members, though they were later printed by the thousands and distributed monthly to libraries, business organizations, public officials and students of economics both domestically and abroad. Eventually, the Chamber began binding bulletins in yearly editions, and members received a personalized copy. While each individual monthly bulletin contains a table of contents, the bound volumes are also indexed for ease of use.
  - Supplements, 1958-1970s (Box 374, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 1, 1909 April-1910 April (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1910 May-1911 April (Box 165, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 3, 1911 May-1912 April (Box 165, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 4, 1912 May-1913 April (Box 165, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 5, 1913 May-1914 April (Box 166, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 6, 1914 May-1915 April (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 7, 1915 May-1916 April (Box 166, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 8, 1916 May-1917 April (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 9, 1917 May-1918 April (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 10, 1918 May-1919 April (Box 167, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 11, 1919 May-1920 April (Box 167, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 12, 1920 May-1921 April (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 13, 1921 May-1922 April (Box 168, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 14, 1922 May-1923 April (Box 168, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 15, 1923 May-1924 April (Box 168, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 16, 1924 May-1925 April (Box 168, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 17, 1925 May-1926 April (Box 169, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 18, 1926 May-1927 April (Box 169, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 19, 1927 May-1928 April (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 20, 1928 May-1929 April (Box 169, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 21, 1929 May-1930 April (Box 169, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 22, 1930 May-1931 April (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 23, 1931 May-1932 April (Box 170, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 24, 1932 May-1933 April (Box 170, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 25, 1933 May-1934 April (Box 170, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 26, 1934 May-1935 April (Box 170, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 27, 1935 May-1936 April (Box 170, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 28, 1936 May-1937 April (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 29, 1937 May-1938 April (Box 171, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 30, 1938 May-1939 April (Box 171, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 31, 1939 May-1940 April (Box 171, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 32, 1940 May-1941 April (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 33, 1941 May-1942 April (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 34, 1942 May-1943 April (Box 172, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 35, 1943 May-1944 April (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 36, 1944 May-1945 April (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 37, 1945 May-1946 April (Box 173, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 38, 1946 May-1947 April (Box 173, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 39, 1947 May-1948 April (Box 173, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 40, 1948 May-1949 April (Box 174, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 41, 1949 May-1950 April (Box 174, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 42, 1950 May-1951 April (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 43, 1951 May-1952 April (Box 175, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 44, 1952 May-1953 April (Box 175, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 45, 1953 May-1954 April (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 46, 1954 May-1955 April (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 47, 1955 May-1956 April (Box 176, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 48, 1956 May-1957 April (Box 176, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 49, 1957 May-1958 April (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 50, 1958 May-1959 April (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 51, 1959 May-1960 April (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 52, 1960 May-1961 April (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 53, 1961 May-1962 April (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 54, 1962 May-1963 April (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 55, 1963 May-1963 December (Box 392, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Commerce and Industry Association, 1873-1978
  The fourth series in the collection is arguably the most complex. It is comprised of the records of the Commerce and Industry Association, an organization similar to the Chamber of Commerce in purpose, which eventually merged with the Chamber in 1973 following a decline in both organizations' membership and corresponding influence. Researchers should note that these records date back to 1873; therefore documents from the Merchants' Association, an earlier incarnation of the Commerce and Industry Association, are included. This series is divided into six subseries according to format or purpose; because of this, each individual subseries closely mirrors the series in the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry collection as a whole.
  - Subseries IV.1: Administration, 1935-1973
    The first subseries contains records related to the administrative tasks of the Commerce and Industry Association. Though relatively small, the subject matter is broad in scope, including a small selection of annual reports, public relations materials, and information on the merger with the New York Chamber of Commerce. Of particular interest in this series are the printed transcripts from the Association's Business Forum Radio broadcasts which ran for several years in the 1940s and billed itself as a "public service program." Additionally, materials related to the Association's merger with the Chamber of Commerce can be found here. Items are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Affiliations
      - Business and Education Council of New York, 1958-1960 (Box 331, Folder 1)
      - Five Counties Taxpayers Defense, 1948-1967 (Box 331, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report
      - 1940-1947 (Box 339, Folder 9)
      - 1948-1960 (Box 339, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report to Members, 1950-1951 (Box 339, Folder 11)
    - Business Forum Radio Broadcasts
      - 1942 November-1943 March (Box 220, Folder 1)
      - 1943 March-October (Box 220, Folder 2)
      - 1943 October-December (Box 220, Folder 3)
      - 1944 January-March (Box 220, Folder 4)
      - 1944 April-September (Box 220, Folder 5)
      - 1944 October (Box 220, Folder 6)
      - 1944 November-1945 January (Box 221, Folder 1)
      - 1945 February-April (Box 221, Folder 2)
      - 1945 May (Box 221, Folder 3)
      - 1945 September-December (Box 221, Folder 4)
      - 1946 January-March (Box 221, Folder 5)
      - 1946 March-September (Box 222, Folder 1)
      - 1946 October-December (Box 222, Folder 2)
      - 1947 January-April (Box 222, Folder 3)
    - Certificate of Incorporation and Bylaws, 1941 (Box 331, Folder 3)
    - Creation of the Commerce and Industry Association Institute, 1960-1973 (Box 331, Folder 4)
    - History
      - Facts, and Organization, 1947 (Box 331, Folder 5)
      - "Facts Concerning the Historical Background, Organization, Physical Facilities and Finances of the Commerce and Industry Association," 1947 (Box 331, Folder 6)
    - Merger with Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York
      - Preparation, 1947, (2 Folders) (Box 331, Folder 7-8)